chapter two intelligent esence in this
chapter we will talk about how to design
intelligent agents and what are the
considerations that we have to make when
designing intelligent agents we really
start with the definition of an asset
earlier we discussed about isn't but did
we didn't provide a specific definition
about isn't here we will define isn't it
specifically for the purpose of
designing intelligent essence and isn't
is anything that can be viewed as
perceiving the environment through
sensors and by acting on the environment
using actuators so if this is our isn't
let's say here's our isn't isn't then
for an isn't to be an isn't for the
purpose of designing intelligent isn't
we define isn't to perceive the
environment if this is our environment
then the agent will perceive the
environment using sensors and it uses
something like as actuators to take
actions on the environment so when
defining isn't it is extremely important
that we mention about environment
mention that the isn't had sensors and
also that the isn't has actuators to act
upon the environment and this diagram
shows how in isn't interacts with the
environment through sensors and
actuators it is also important to note
that sensors and actuators are the part
of the isn't itself whereas the
environment is outside there isn't the
environment is where there is an
interaction axon now as examples of
esence the human isn't has eyes ears and
other organs as sensors right so if this
is a
one isn't then the census for the human
isn't will be these that can be used to
perceive the environment and hands legs
vocal tract etc are actuators and that's
what we use to take accents on the
environment
another example is a robotic isn't for a
robotic isn't cameras and infrared range
finders can act as sensors for the robot
and the various mortars can act as
actuators for example if you have a
self-driving car then wheels and various
mortars that the robot had can be used
as actuators to act upon the environment
another example is a software isn't
software isn't can for a software isn't
it sensory inputs can be the keystrokes
it receives file contents and network
packets and then it can act upon the
environment by displaying on the screen
writing to files and sending it or
packets and so on
when talking about essence and how
essence perceive the environment it is
important that we understand the
difference between a percept and a
percept sequence so percept is an
essence perceptual input at any given
instant at one instant of time so say
for example if we have a robotic isn't
then what does the robotic isn't
perceived at one single instant of time
that is what picture it is viewing or
what from infrared sensor it is taking
from the input and so on so percept is
the input at a single instant of time
whereas percept sequence is a complete
history of everything that the essent
has ever perceived so if we are talking
about let's say the human isn't then the
percept sequence will be everything that
the human isn't has ever received
through his or her eyes ears and and
other sensory organs since the birth of
that human when talking about essence it
is also important that we understand the
difference between two things
isn't function and isn't program so see
you are given a new isn't right we don't
know what that is and does so here's
your isn't we don't know what the ad
isn't ours and we would like to know
what the Hedden isn't does in other
words we are looking for something like
an instruction manual for the ezzat
right now the instruction manual for the
essent can be written or described at
two levels one level is to describe
something known as essent function and
the other is to describe something on
this isn't program to better describe
these two let's take a take an example
of something known as a vacuum cleaner
world say we have a vacuum cleaner isn't
here's our vacuum cleaner isn't vacuum
cleaner isn't and the problem that we
have is we have two rooms room a and
room B two rooms two rooms and these
these like in a store like things
represent Thoth in the room so room a
maybe 30 and room B maybe 30 and romaine
maybe clean and B maybe clean and so on
so our vacuum cleaner isn't has to go to
either of these two rooms and suck this
dot that is clean these rooms room two
and room room room a and room B so in
this vacuum cleaner world we just have
two locations one is a square a and
square B or room a or Ruby and what we
have is a vacuum isn't which perceives
which can perceive two things which can
perceive which square it is in and if
there is a dirt in the spatter not so
this vacuum cleaner can only perceive
two things one it can perceive which
room it is currently at and second it
can perceive whether that room has a
tort or not right and as accents the
vacuum cleaner isn't can either move
left move right or suck up the dirt or
do nothing so the essent has these
choices in other words this is how
in Korea interact with the environment
so isn't function is simply something
like a tiny instruction manual that says
here's let's say situation situation and
here's the action
so given this situation what will they
send to do given another situation what
will the essent or given a third
situation what that what does that is
into so this table of all possible
situations or scenarios where there
isn't may receive input and the
corresponding actions is isn't function
so for the vacuum isn't the isn't
function will look something like this
if the current is squad is Authority
then suck the dirt otherwise move to the
other squad right so it characterizes
what happens within various situations
if it is in room a and the room is dirty
then the vacuum will suck the load if it
is in room a and the room is clean and
the vacuum will move to the other room
and it will keep oscillating until all
rooms are clean so this is what isn't
function would represent for the vacuum
comm isn't specifically I can represent
the the isn't function for the vacuum
cleaner isn't using a clean table like
this so the first column is the percept
sequence and the second column is the
action that we want the isn't to take or
the action that the agent takes if the
essent is in room a and the room is
clean then the action that the agent
will take is going to the right if it is
in room a and the room is already clean
then obviously the vacuum isn't will
move to roam be to check if it is clean
enough if it is in room a and the room
is dirty then the vacuum cleaner isn't
will suck the dirt and this is what we
expect in other words this is like your
manual man all instruction manual of
this vacuum cleaner essence right and if
it is in room B if it the room is clean
the
we'll move left if it is in room B and
the room is dirty than theirs and will
suck the door if it is in room a and the
room is clean and if the vacuum cleaner
has and continues to stay in the same
room and if it is in room a and now
again the room is clean then there is it
will move right similarly if it is in
room a room a is clean if it continues
to stay in the same room and if it is in
a and clean and after some time it is
still in the same room and the room
becomes too dirty
then the agent will suck the door so
this this table is basically isn't
function we are we are characterizing
what the isn't does in the form of this
table now isn't program is more like the
underlying working mechanism of this is
in term of this si it's basically the
implementation of how the isn't works
and here's a very simple implementation
of the of the vacuum isn't that we are
working with so it's a it's a function
that takes as input the current location
in the status that is whether it's in
square a square B and whether the square
is dirty or clean and at the end it
returns an action the possible actions
that you can take is either moving to
right or sucking dirt or moving left
right so if status is dirty then no
matter what you room you are in what we
will return is the action will be
sucking the dirt else if the room is not
dirty that is if the room is clean then
if it is in location a then we would
want the wacom intous and to move right
if it is an A then we want in to move
right and if it is in location B then we
want it to return
moving left so this function tiny
function is the essent program for the
vacuum cleaner agent so given our new
isn't we can use s and function and SN
program to characterize what the essent
does so say for example you have a new
asset you don't know what this isn't
does right then what we want to see is
as ant function and as in program of
this is it so that we have a better
understanding of what the what the agent
does get given various scenarios so
isn't function describes an essence
behavior by mapping any given percept
sequence to an action as we saw in the
table earlier to describe any given
isn't we have to tabulate the essent
function and this will typically be a
very large table proper potentially
infinitely large table because we have
to list out every possible scenario in
which the essent may be exposed that in
the corresponding action that the agent
will take and we can in principle
construct this table by trying out all
possible percept sequences and recording
which accents the agent does in response
so once you have created or built an
isn't like this we expose the resin to
all possible environments or all
possible percept sequence s that the
agent can perceive and then record what
the agent does that is what accents the
isn't takes for these possible sequences
and then create a table and that gives
us the SN function so this table is an
external characterization of the essent
in other words here we are ignoring the
details of the isn't that is how the
heads and performs what program is
written inside and rather we are looking
at more abstract mathematical
description of this and that is we are
looking at it from the outside world and
observing the essent and recording what
that is and doesn't various scenarios
the agent program on the other hand is
an internal implementation of the agent
function for an artificially intelligent
agent now this is a concrete
implementation particularly a program a
computer program
that is running within some physical
system either within a computer system
or something similar in the previous
chapter we learned that one of the one
of the best definitions for AI is
designing isn't that act rational right
now how can we define this acting
irrationally so we can write computer
programs because eventually we can talk
about acting rational and we can talk
about many definitions of AI ultimately
within computer science our goal will be
to write computer programs implement or
write programming codes that we can
eventually show or like and prove that
what we have built X rationally or does
rationally so how can we define acting
rationally that's one question that we
will discuss also when talking you are
acting rationally should we consider the
environment where the essent will be
deployed or can we define acting
rationally by ignoring the environment
so a rational isn't in general this is
just in general in general is the one
that does the right thing so this is in
general in general a wrassle isn't is
the one that does the right thing in
other words every entry in the table for
assent forms and is filled out correctly
so given this circumstance the agent
will do this and this all needs to be
filled out appropriately correctly let's
say appropriately now this is not a
definition of a rational isn't but it's
still in general and a rational as it is
something that does the right thing so
what does it exactly mean to say that an
essent is a rational agent is the one
that does the right thing so to
understand this what we need to look at
is we need to consider the consequences
of the esence behavior when an agent is
plopped down in an environment it
generates a sequence of actions
according to the four separate receives
right say for example we build a new
ascent and I throw it to a new
environment let's say for example a
populated environment like this it will
take a lot of actions based on what it
perceives it might keep walking in the
street it might start hurting people or
helping people it might start doing
certain things these sequence of actions
causes the environment to go through a
sequence of states in other words
because now this agent is acting on the
environment the environment will face
some consequences or changes there will
be changes in the environment if this
sequence of environment is desirable
then we can say that the essent has
performed well in other words we have
narrowed down this general definition of
rational assent or rationality to
something that makes more sense in other
words now what we are saying is this
agent may have its own agent program
program it may have its own asn't
function right which may be really good
on their own but what we are looking at
is when this isn't act on this
environment what consequence has
happened to the environment what changes
happen to the environment and are these
changes desirable if these changes are
something that is desirable then we can
say that this isn't is rational
otherwise even though the agent program
may be good and the agent function may
be good if the impact on the environment
is not desirable then we can say that
the isn't is not acting rationally
so the point that we are making here is
we are interested in Environment States
not as any states in other words the
agent may be doing many things within
itself but we are not concerned about
what happens inside the ism
instead what we are concerned about is
what happens to the environment this is
what we are more concerned about so we
should not define the success of an
assent in terms of the agents opinion
the isn't could achieve a perfect
rationality simply by diluting itself
that its performance was perfect the
hasn't might say I might say this is
what I was designed for I did exactly
what I was supposed to do but the impact
on the environment may not be very good
right and human essence for example are
very notorious for sour grapes right so
if you cannot reach out to if you can
finish the task but if you don't achieve
something we always make very good
excuses by saying that there were some
other reasons for for us not being
successful or not achieving what what we
really needed to achieve so in other
words what we want to do is a defined
rationality in the context of the
changes to the environment rather than
the changes to the agent itself so the
performance measure that we define in
other words our evaluation metric to
evaluate how good our isn't is or how
bad our as it is should focus on
environment rather than what the essence
should behave so when we are when we are
designing new essence are creating or
building new essence we should design
our performance measures according to
what we want in the environment rather
than how the agent should behave
because we may go on and on and spend a
lot of time trying to decide what the
his insured behave and what the isn't
should do but ultimately what matters is
the impact on the environment so our
performance measures should be based on
what we want in the environment for
example for the vacuum isn't that we had
we proposed to measure the performance
by the amount of dirt cleaned up in a
single ate shift our let's say we have
the vacuum cleaner isn't right isn't and
what we want to do is design and isn't
that can clean as much dirt as possible
that is we are trying to our performance
measure to evaluate how good the agent
is is this we want to check the amount
of dirt clean up in an eight-hour shift
right now this looks like a really good
performance measure to evaluate or to
check how good the the agent is but
there's something wrong with this
performance measure and here's what's
wrong what there isn't might do is in
the first second collect some dirt and
then in the second second throw it back
to the environment and then pick it up
again and throw it back to the
environment and pick it up again and
repeat this over and over again so in a
tower the agent will have collected a
lot of dirt if you measure the amount of
dirt that there is and collected it will
look quite a lot of dirt but it's
collecting more dirt because it's
throwing the dirt back to the
environment in other words this
definition although it looks a really
good definition of evaluating our vacuum
isn't doesn't take into account all the
possible impacts on the environment
right so this is an example where our
performance measure should be designed
such that it addresses exactly what we
want in the environment
so overall what is rational at any given
time depends on four things the
performance measure that defines the
criteria of success the essence prior
knowledge of the environment the accent
that the agent can perform and the
agents percept sequence to debt now we
are getting into really tricky defining
rationality in a really tricky way so
say for example we design a vacuum
cleaner isn't let's say our vacuum
cleaner isn't and our performance
measure is like the one before that is
amount of dirt amount of dirt cleaned
clean right so this is our performance
measure so let's say we design a vacuum
cleaner and this is our performance
measure and what the vacuum cleaner does
is it collects dirt throws it back to
the environment collects more dirt
throws it back to the environment and
oscillates cleaning the dirt then this
vacuum cleaner isn't is rational it is
rational it is rational it is not
irrational because it binds to our
definition of performance measure in
other words it meets our performance
criteria so what is rational depends on
what our performance measure is
rationality also depends on the agents
prior knowledge say for example we have
a lot of rooms just like room a and room
B where we have room a b c d and let's
say there's a vacuum cleaner
isn't that comes comes to room a tries
to clean the torture even though there
is no toad goes to room B again cleans
the toad goes to room C and again cleans
the door so based on how we define try
based on what the hesita already knows
it may be rational for the agent to suck
the dirt in every room because it may
not know that every room doesn't every
room is is not clean
also rationality depends on what accents
the agent can perform so if you're let's
say we have a square room that the agent
has access to and is it he's supposed to
clean and let's say the agent cannot
clean the corners in other words
physically the agent is not capable of
cleaning the corners so then it is
rational for the agent to not clean the
corners because it cannot perform such
actions right so rationality also
depends on what the Hessian can perform
it also depends on the agents percept
sequence to date that is what the agent
has learned over time so now let's look
at a formal definition of a rational
agent how can we define an isn't that is
resolved for each possible possible
sequence a rational isn't a rational
isn't should select an action that is
expected to maximise its performance
measure this is the most important part
maximize its performance measure given
the evidence provided by the percept
sequence and whatever built-in knowledge
the isn't has now you may be thinking
that a robot is good a robot let's say a
robot is good if it saves humanity right
but this is not true because in the
definition of rational isn't what we are
saying is an isn't is rational if it
tries to maximize its performance
measure it doesn't say either save
humanity or harm humanity and essent is
rational if it does what it's designed
to do if it is designed to hold people
and if it if there isn't exactly does
that then we say that there isn't is
rational if it is designed to save human
t of save people in various
circumstances and if it does that then
once again we call that isn't as
rational we can have pre-loaded
knowledge into the isn't all of the
agent may go through a percept sequence
and learn something about the
environment to act upon the environment
but what is rational depends on on what
performance measure that we we use so
and isn't is rational if it maximizes or
if it is if it tries to maximize the
performance measure that it is designed
for here's an example that demonstrates
the problems with performance measures
let us assume the following for the
vacuum cleaner example let's say our
performance measure is this we award one
point for each clean a square at each
time step over the lifetime of 1,000
time steps that is every time the vacuum
cleaner isn't makes the room clean or
perceive the room as clean we award it
one point the prior knowledge that the
agent has is there are two squares but
it doesn't know the dot distribution
that is every time either of these two
rooms can be dirty or clean the
available actions are left right and
sucking the route and the poor ship
sequence is simply that the agent
product it perceives its location and
whether the location contents daughter
laughs so here is what the vacuum
cleaner isn't will do it cleans a square
if it is dirty and moves to the other
square if it is not right so every time
it goes to a navy square it will try to
collect at one point if it the room is
clean otherwise it will our is this
vacuum cleaner isn't irrational or not
so the performance measure is that every
time it cleans a square it gets one
point so to get that it cleans a square
if it is too dirty and then move to the
other square so it definitely tries to
increase this performance measure
it uses the prior knowledge it uses all
the actions available and it perceives
percept sequence correctly so now
clearly the isn't is vacuum cleaner
isn't is rational because it tries to
maximize the performance measure the
question is is the performance measure
robust that is our criteria for
evaluating the rationality you are
evaluating how good our vacuum is this
correct or is this good enough or not
that's the question so here here's a
problem that can happen once the essent
cleans up all the dirt
what does it do it will oscillate back
and forth in other words it will go to
room a clean the board go to room B
clean the dirt come back to room a and
go back to room B and keep oscillating
between room a and room B almost forever
whether the rooms are clean or dirty but
still the agent will be rational because
it is still tries to maximize the
performance measure we didn't explicitly
say that the haysoms should not
oscillate right so here the problem is
with the performance measure that is the
agent is rational but our performance
measure is not good enough to capture
what we want in the environment so to
correctly specify what an agent should
do our first step must be to specify
something known as the task environment
as fully as possible so what do we mean
by a task environment a task environment
is a combination of four things one is
the performance measure another it is
specifying the environment another is
actuators that the isn't may have an ins
listing out the sensors that the main
isn't must have here's an example a
fully automated taxi let's say we have
it we would like to design and isn't
that is basically an automatic taxi
Piper right is them this is an extremely
challenging task to design a fully
automated taxi but before we design this
isn't we need to list correctly the
piece of this essence for this asset so
our P performance measure will be
something like the taxi has to be safe
it has to be fast it has to be legal it
has to give a comfortable trip it has to
maximize profits for the owners right
owners it also should work in all
weather conditions so these are our
performance measures the environment
will be the essent will interact with
the following environment roads or the
traffic pedestrians and customers and so
on the actuators available for the isn't
are stealing acceleration brake signal
horn display and the sensors that the
agent has to perceive with the
environmental cameras GPS Auto Meter
accelerometer or engine sensors keyboard
for a person to interact and so on so
when designing isn't it is important
that we specify these four things
performance measure environment
actuators and sensors for the ascent
time so that this can then be further
used to either make NSN function or or
an agent program or an isn't program
here are some more examples of correctly
specifying a task environment say for
example we have a online medical
diagnosis system let's say for example
of WebMD right so then the ascent type
is a medical diagnostic system the
performance measure will be something
like healthy peasant and reduced costs
not correct diagnosis because there may
be examples where the isn't may do
correct diagnosis but that may not lead
to a healthy peasant the environment
would be peasant hospital staff and so
on for a satellite imaging analysis
system correct image categorization may
be the performance measure for part
picking robot the percentage of parts in
correct beans not the percentage of
parts picked correctly because the
might pick up the parts correctly but
then it may not place it into the right
bins right so what we need to look into
when we are trying to come up with
performance metrics is the impact in the
environment it should correctly capture
what impact we want in the environment
similarly for a refinery controller the
performance measure may be purity yearly
safety for an interactive English tutor
an online tutor the performance measure
will be something like the students
score on the test not how well the
teacher teaches because the teacher
always may claim that the teacher is
teaching very well and we may come up
with many metrics to prove that but
eventually a tutors ultimate goal is to
help the students score better on the
test right so this should be our
performance mirror that it correctly
evaluates the impact in the environment
in summary in this chapter what we saw
is an isn't it's something that
perceives and acts in an environment we
talked about and isn't having sensors
actuators and interacting with the
environment and isn't function is for
inherently specify the actions taken by
the ears and in response to partial
sequence we also discussed that
performance measure evaluates the
behavior often isn't in an environment a
rational isn't is is an isn't that there
is expected to maximize the performance
measure maximize the performance measure
given the positive sequence it has seen
so far a task environment is defining
for things that is performance measure
environment actuators and sensors and in
designing an desn't we saw that the
first step must be to specify the task
environment as fully as possible